Bodhisattwa Baidya

Kolkata | bodhisattwabaidya@gmail.com | +919051504557 https://orcid.org/my-orcid?orcid=0009-0002-3663-4497 | linkedin.com/in/bodhisattwa-baidya github.com/Bodhi1998

Biography

Bodhisattwa Baidya, a mentor at AIEYS, is a passionate aviation enthusiast and research scholar from Kolkata, India. With degrees in Computer Applications, he's pursuing a Ph.D. in Computer Science at Ramakrishna Mission Vidyamandira while working as a Teaching Assistant. His expertise lies in drone security, cryptography, and AI-enabled drones, with research published in IEEE. As an FPV drone pilot, he brings practical experience to his academic work. Bodhisattwa is a member of Qoptars Pvt Ltd and the International Association of Engineers (IAENG). He actively engages in scholarly activities as a book editor and reviewer, with many publications pending. He has received recognition as a C20 Delegate, won an Inter-College Technical Quiz Championship at IIT Delhi, and earned a Young Researcher Certificate from AIEYS and ICETI. Bodhisattwa is also a sought-after keynote speaker at international conferences, solidifying his reputation in the field.

Education

Ludduon	
Ramakrishna Mission Vidyamandira,Belur Math,India, Phd in Computer Science	June 2024 – Present
• Coursework: Wireless AD-Hoc Network, UAV Security, Research Methodology	
Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham,India, Master of Computer Application	August 2021 – July 2023
• Coursework: Machine Learning, SDN, Computer Architecture	
Experience	
Member, International Association of Engineers Member(IAENG) – Hong Kong	September 2024 – Present
Mentor, AI-Explain You Science (AI-EYS)	October 2004 – Present
Teaching Assistant,Ramakrishna Mission Vidyamandira,Belur Math,India	July 2024 – Present
Drone Developer, Qoptars Pvt Ltd.	February 2022 – Present
Summer Internship, Oil and Natural Gas Corporation Ltd (ONGC)	August 2019 – October 2019

Publications

- (1)Baidya, Bodhisattwa, and P. K. Binu. "An Efficient Path Selection in Software Defined UAV Network." In 2023 14th International Conference on Computing Communication and Networking Technologies (ICCCNT), pp. 1-7. IEEE, 2023.
- (2)Baidya, B., Mondal, A., Abdullah, S. H., Tawfiq, A. T., Arshi, O. (2024). Quantum-Resistant UAV System Using Lattice-Based Key Agreement Protocol. In Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Advances in Communication Technologies and Computer Engineering (ICACTCE'24), Springer(Accepted)
- (3)B. Baidya, A. Mondal, S. Manna, G. Das, A. Santra, and A. Chakraborty, "Enhanced UAV Tracking through Multi-Sensor Fusion and Extended Kalman Filtering," in 2024 Sixth Doctoral Symposium on Intelligence Enabled Research (DoSIER 2024), (Accepted)
- (4)Bodhisattwa Baidya and Atanu Mondal, "Quantum-Resistant Lattice-Based Cryptography for Secure UAV Communications," Smart Systems and Wireless Communication(SSWC2024), Springer(Accepted)
- (5)Baidya, B., Mondal, A., Hundekari, S., Khan, I. U., S N, P., Kaushik, K. (2024). Quantum Lattice: Securing UAV Swarms in the Post-Quantum Era. In Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Pervasive Computing Advances and Applications (PerCAA-2024),IET(Accepted)
- (6)Baidya, B., Mallick, S., Mondal, A., Anamalamudi, S. (2024). Energy-Efficient UAV Path Planning using PSO-ABC algorithm in Obstacle-Rich Environments. In Proceedings of the 22nd OITS International Conference on Information Technology (OCIT 2024). IEEE(Accepted)